<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-02-12T18:22:30-08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Poppy’s Seeds Farm</title><subtitle>A blog about homesteading, crafting, raising critters, and everything in between.</subtitle><author><name>Sarah</name></author><entry><title type="html">Fine Art Fridays: February 12, 2021</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/crafts/2021/02/12/fineartfriday02.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fine Art Fridays: February 12, 2021" /><published>2021-02-12T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-02-12T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/crafts/2021/02/12/fineartfriday02</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/crafts/2021/02/12/fineartfriday02.html">&lt;p&gt;Happy Friday! I have been so busy getting to work with my Cricut machine, planning and dreaming about the upcoming additions to the farm, and quilting that I haven't been posting much. However, I did want to share some of the things I have been sketching. Maybe it's because bee season is just around the corner, or maybe I just have bugs on the brain, but beekeeping equipment has been floating around my brain recently and showing up a lot in my art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Featured this week is a little sketch I've been working on featuring some items that make me think of the bees (except the onion... I'm honestly not sure why I drew that, but oh well). Next week I'll be getting back into the groove with regular hive inspections, so stay tuned for some posts about what to look for during hive inspections and how to make springtime splits!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for following along this week. More to come this weekend and in the coming weeks!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;</content><author><name>Sarah</name></author><category term="crafts" /><category term="painting" /><category term="art" /><category term="crafts" /><summary type="html">Happy Friday! I have been so busy getting to work with my Cricut machine, planning and dreaming about the upcoming additions to the farm, and quilting that I haven't been posting much. However, I did want to share some of the things I have been sketching. Maybe it's because bee season is just around the corner, or maybe I just have bugs on the brain, but beekeeping equipment...</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/fineartfriday2_email.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/fineartfriday2_email.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">One-day Sourdough Recipe</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/baking/2021/02/07/onedaysourdough.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One-day Sourdough Recipe" /><published>2021-02-07T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-02-07T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/baking/2021/02/07/onedaysourdough</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/baking/2021/02/07/onedaysourdough.html">&lt;p&gt;Before I made my first loaf of sourdough, I remember being intimidated. Intimidated by the amount of time it takes to make it, the fact that you need to have a starter of some kind, and the general supposed fussiness surrounding the whole project. I had been told so many times that sourdough is hard to make. In a way, yes, artisan sourdough, the best of the best, takes a lot of time, patience and skill. But, if you want to make yummy, simple sourdough for your friends and family, it really isn't as hard as it seems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to learn how to make two sourdough loaves in one day? Here's how I do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;This recipe is not my own, and it is not necessarily the &quot;right&quot; way to make sourdough. It works for me, so I use it when I want to make bread in a day.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;If you want more information on skills like stretching and folding (rather than kneading), autolyse, or other traditional sourdough preparation methods, I am likely going to make a series of other posts where I try out these slower tactics for making a more perfect loaf. This recipe (with my own tweaks) comes from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilovecooking.ie/features/sourdough-bread-masterclass-with-patrick-ryan/&quot;&gt;I Love Cooking Ireland&lt;/a&gt; and has been one of my go-to recipes, since it is so easy and quick to make! The result is delicious and beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Helpful Links to Get You Started&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sarah0a4-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;placement=B089LVDXGB&amp;asins=B089LVDXGB&amp;linkId=d53cbc0c7b93c031794d2047e8a31415&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=2d2d2d&amp;title_color=ffc7c7&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sarah0a4-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;placement=B073Q9PSWD&amp;asins=B073Q9PSWD&amp;linkId=05f4405a81be02d18d27bbc4947cd162&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=2d2d2d&amp;title_color=ffc7c7&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sarah0a4-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;placement=B00UIVIXVO&amp;asins=B00UIVIXVO&amp;linkId=f8e9b4c4d50d4462b59b217f40b76317&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=2d2d2d&amp;title_color=ffc7c7&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sarah0a4-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;placement=B08QMKJ646&amp;asins=B08QMKJ646&amp;linkId=79bce6c2c9be509eeaa82dae7e6483eb&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=2d2d2d&amp;title_color=ffc7c7&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sarah0a4-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;placement=B01LY7NDQ9&amp;asins=B01LY7NDQ9&amp;linkId=071c68867c9e42e3bd8d9d62c3993f15&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=2d2d2d&amp;title_color=ffc7c7&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ok, let's get at it!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Scroll to bottom of the page for a short, itemized recipe)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/whatyouneed.jpg&quot;&gt;First, make sure your starter has some nice, big bubbles on the sides and top. It is best to use starter that was fed within the last 6-10 hours. You know your starter, so whatever time frame works for you to catch it right at the top of its rise is the best time. I've used my starter for this in many different stages of rise, so it's not a huge deal if you fed it 5 hours ago and it's still on the up. My recommendation is to feed it the night before, then start your bread right away in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;If you need to make a starter, never fear!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; I like this step-by-step from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theclevercarrot.com/2019/03/beginner-sourdough-starter-recipe/&quot;&gt;The Clever Carrot&lt;/a&gt;. Come on back in a week or so once you've got a lovely, bubbly starter of your own! And don't forget to give it a name, since it's basically a new pet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Measure out with your scale 800g of flour (the recipe from ILCI says strong white flour, but for this I am using about 500g of whole wheat King Arthur flour and 300g of &lt;a href=&quot;http://giustos.com/home_baker/flours/snowflake-all-purpose-unbleached-white-flour.html&quot;&gt;Giusto's Snowflake Flour&lt;/a&gt;, which is an unbleached white flour that is made by a local miller). Put the flour into a large bowl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/autolyse.jpg&quot;&gt;Measure out 460ml of room-temperature water. Add this to the flour in the bowl, and stir together. I like to combine the flour and water first and stir together to give it a chance to combine. It's like a mini autolyse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, add about 10g of salt. I usually go for about 12g, since my family likes the sourdough to be more flavorful and salty. Stir everything together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it's time to add your starter. Measure 320g of starter and add to your mixture. It should start to come together as a shaggy dough ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;At this point, you can either transfer to a stand mixer or knead by hand.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first made this recipe, I didn't have a mixer. It is not a requirement in any way and honestly I usually will bring the dough out of the mixer at a certain point to finish kneading by hand. Bread-making is such a hands-on process that it is hard to know exactly when it's ready to rise when using a stand mixer alone (in my opinion).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Now it's time to knead, mix, and stretch that dough!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/windpaneno.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/windowpane.jpg&quot;&gt;You will notice a moment where it goes from being a shaggy, sticky ball to being smooth and pliable. It will seem to want to stick together. At that point, you can cut off a piece using your bread rib (link above) and hold it up. As the dough falls, it will either tear apart or, if it is ready, it will create a windowpane-like membrane. If the dough holds together and you can see light through it, you know that your gluten is strong and holding together. That means it's time to let the bread rise. If it is still tearing, knead for a little longer. I promise the bread will tell you when it is ready!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Bring your bread back together and transfer to a large bowl. Let it sit on the counter, covered, for about 3 hours.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some breads require proving in the oven with the light on but I do not recommend that with sourdough. It does really well at room temperature, as the starter eats the flour you've basically fed to it. Commercial and package yeasts like and can handle heat, but high heat is the enemy of sourdough starter. For that reason I also advise you not leave the bread to rise in a sunny place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Now you can get on with your day for a few hours! Let it sit and do its thing.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/proofone.jpg&quot;&gt; 3 hours have passed, remove your bread from the bowl. Flatten it slightly to &quot;knock it back&quot;, and start stretching the corners over each other to create a ball. Do this by feel-- you're really just trying to quickly and gently knock some air out of it, and then re-form it into a nice, round shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Now you can split your bread into two even sections and start to shape your loaves!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/doughshapingcompare.jpg&quot;&gt;Cut your bread into two even sections and shape them one at a time. While shaping, you want to create surface tension on the sides of your loaf. The easiest way to shape is to pull one corner at a time into the center of your ball of dough to create a round shape. Then, put one hand on the top of the dough ball and one on the side, with your fingertips touching. Drag the dough backwards one time. Then, flip it 45 degrees and drag again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Once you're done shaping, you can put your loaves into a floured bread banneton (link above) or a floured, towel-lined Pyrex dish. Then, you guessed it, it's time to let that bread rise again.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/breadinbasketproof2.jpg&quot;&gt;Cover your breads with a towel (if you're using a towel-lined Pyrex dish, you can just wrap the towel around the top of the bread) and let them sit for another 3-4 hours. You can, at this point, put them in the fridge to rise overnight if it's getting late. I personally prefer not to do this since I feel like I have less control over the speed of the rise, but if you are in a time crunch, it will rise just fine in the fridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;After 3 hours, check on your breads. My tried and true way to know if they're ready is to poke them very gently with my middle finger. If they bounce back, they are ready. If not, let prove for another 30 minutes to an hour.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put your dutch ovens into the oven. Preheat, with the ovens inside, to 460°F. I like to have my dutch ovens already warm before I put the bread in. If you don't have a dutch oven, you can use a casserole dish with a lid. It is important to have a lid, because the bread needs to steam while it's in the oven in order to rise well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/scoredbread.jpg&quot;&gt;Flip your breads gently out of the basket or Pyrex dish onto a tray or cutting board. Now it's time to score your loaves! This is your time to be creative. Using a bread scoring blade (link above) or just a very sharp paring knife, cut into the top a design or simple cut. This lets the air escape the bread and helps with the rising in the oven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transfer your breads to your warmed dutch ovens. They do not have to be the full 460°F of the oven, but having them warmed gives a head start to the rising process. Cover with the lids and put in the oven for 25 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;After 25 minutes, take the lids off and bake for another 25 minutes. The first 25 are for the bread to steam and rise, and the next 25 are for the bread to get nice and crispy.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/breadpostlast.jpg&quot;&gt;Remove your breads and let them rest for a while. But, let's be real, I usually wait all of 10-15 minutes, just as long as it takes to not burn my hands handling them. Slice and serve!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did your loaves turn out? Let me know via email, &lt;a href=&quot;http://instagram.com/poppysseedsfarm&quot;&gt; Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://facebook.com/poppys.seeds&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. Happy baking!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Recipe adapted from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilovecooking.ie/features/sourdough-bread-masterclass-with-patrick-ryan/&quot;&gt;I Love Cooking Ireland&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;1.&lt;/b&gt; 500g whole wheat flour, 300g unbleached white flour (or 800g flour of choice)&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;2.&lt;/b&gt; 10-12g salt&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;2.&lt;/b&gt; 10-12g salt&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;3.&lt;/b&gt; 460ml water&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;4.&lt;/b&gt; 320g sourdough starter&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;5.&lt;/b&gt; Add the flour and water to a large bowl and stir together to combine. Mix the salt throughout. Add the sourdough starter.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;6.&lt;/b&gt; Combine all the ingredients together to form a shaggy dough. Note: Do not add any extra flour, even when kneading! The dough is meant to be wet and sticky.&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;7.&lt;/b&gt; Transfer the dough to a stand mixer or the counter and knead until the dough can stretch without ripping (the &quot;windowpane&quot; effect).&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;8.&lt;/b&gt; Let the dough rise in a bowl for 3 hours at room temperature. Avoid sunny or overly warm areas.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;9.&lt;/b&gt; Lightly punch the dough to knock out air and equilize the temperature within the bread. Bring back into a ball and cut into two equal loaves.&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;10.&lt;/b&gt; Shape your loaves and transfer to a floured bread basket or floured, towel-lined Pyrex dish.&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;11.&lt;/b&gt; Let rise for 4 more hours.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;12.&lt;/b&gt; Preheat oven to 460°F with dutch ovens inside.&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;13.&lt;/b&gt; Turn out dough onto a baking sheet or cutting board. Score the top using a sharp blade.&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;14.&lt;/b&gt; Transfer scored loaves to warmed dutch ovens. Put the lids on and bake for 25 minutes.&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;15.&lt;/b&gt; Remove the lids and bake for another 25 minutes, to brown the top.&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;16.&lt;/b&gt; Remove bread when it is crispy and golden-brown.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;</content><author><name>Sarah</name></author><category term="baking" /><category term="kitchen" /><category term="baking" /><summary type="html">Before I made my first loaf of sourdough, I remember being intimidated. Intimidated by the amount of time it takes to make it, the fact that you need to have a starter of some kind, and the general supposed fussiness surrounding the whole project. I had been told so many times that sourdough is hard to make. In a way, yes, artisan sourdough, the best of the best, takes a lot of time, patience and skill. But, if you want to make yummy, simple sourdough for your friends and family, it really isn't as hard as it seems...</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/breadpost_email.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/breadpost_email.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Fine Art Fridays: February 5, 2021</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/crafts/2021/02/05/fineartfriday01.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fine Art Fridays: February 5, 2021" /><published>2021-02-05T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-02-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/crafts/2021/02/05/fineartfriday01</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/crafts/2021/02/05/fineartfriday01.html">&lt;p&gt;Happy Friday! I have been working on a lot of new artistic projects this week, and I thought it would be fun to start a &quot;Fine Art Friday&quot; tradition here on the blog. Currently, I have been making a lot of animated gifs (as you can see scattered around the site)! I finally got a Cricut machine and I am really excited to start learning how to make stickers, which has also prompted the grand opening of our &lt;a href=&quot;http://poppysseedsfarm.bigcartel.com/&quot;&gt;shop&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please stop by and check it out when you get the chance. There are limited supplies of current items, but I would love to hear any feedback you have on what items you would like to see more or less of in the shop. There are only two sticker options available at the moment as I figure out my Cricut, but please check back frequently if you are interested in more styles. I will be designing more! I also have a sweatshirt available, with more clothing options also coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/fineartfriday1.gif&quot;&gt;I'll leave you with this sweet little animated GIF that I made for my sister. Thanks for following along, have a wonderful weekend!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sarah</name></author><category term="crafts" /><category term="painting" /><category term="art" /><category term="crafts" /><summary type="html">Happy Friday! I have been working on a lot of new artistic projects this week, and I thought it would be fun to start a &quot;Fine Art Friday&quot; tradition here on the blog. This week, I have been making a lot of animated gifs (as you can see scattered around the site)! I finally got a Cricut machine and I am really excited to start learning how to make stickers, which has prompted the grand opening of our sho...</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/chickensticker_email.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/chickensticker_email.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Raising Quails From Chicks to Adults</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/quails/2021/02/03/quailchicks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Raising Quails From Chicks to Adults" /><published>2021-02-03T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-02-03T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/quails/2021/02/03/quailchicks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/quails/2021/02/03/quailchicks.html">&lt;p&gt;Raising quails from chicks can be very rewarding. My quails are very friendly and comfortable around me, and I attribute that to the fact that I hatched and raised them myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are able to hatch your own chicks, or are fortunate to purchase some day old chicks, here is a quick and easy guide for hatching, brooding, and caring for chicks from day one to adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's my quick and easy pocket guide to quail chicks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Helpful Links to Get You Started:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sarah0a4-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;placement=B004XNVD7E&amp;asins=B004XNVD7E&amp;linkId=412789ff39004fbb0e5ad3ffdb98d31e&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=2d2d2d&amp;title_color=ffc7c7&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sarah0a4-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;placement=B07NJZM1F5&amp;asins=B07NJZM1F5&amp;linkId=ce5fc2341fcef17411fae61100c71be8&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=2d2d2d&amp;title_color=ffc7c7&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sarah0a4-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;placement=B000BO58PW&amp;asins=B000BO58PW&amp;linkId=bba93cd9f2092c3a3b4a7bda6bc7d81b&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=2d2d2d&amp;title_color=ffc7c7&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sarah0a4-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;placement=B000MVGZI8&amp;asins=B000MVGZI8&amp;linkId=a122917239c28f2b3fb8d0a37fb82a61&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=2d2d2d&amp;title_color=ffc7c7&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sarah0a4-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;placement=B000HHLO4W&amp;asins=B000HHLO4W&amp;linkId=398e070701353ff5b0e8c93cba41bc5a&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=2d2d2d&amp;title_color=ffc7c7&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sarah0a4-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;placement=B00FBRJA76&amp;asins=B00FBRJA76&amp;linkId=1d28611d54918e77778fdd5aedde1974&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=2d2d2d&amp;title_color=ffc7c7&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sarah0a4-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;placement=B074FH47MQ&amp;asins=B074FH47MQ&amp;linkId=33e30f684c3a549d50a224287a2b7d41&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=2d2d2d&amp;title_color=ffc7c7&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sarah0a4-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;placement=B089ZVDVLL&amp;asins=B089ZVDVLL&amp;linkId=10a40b2f2ba199990aec768f538af95f&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=2d2d2d&amp;title_color=ffc7c7&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sarah0a4-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;placement=B071H2RJMG&amp;asins=B071H2RJMG&amp;linkId=9c01fc257cae1330904c89b127c21ffd&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=2d2d2d&amp;title_color=ffc7c7&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hatching:&lt;/b&gt; I highly recommend using the Hovabator Genesis Incubator linked above. After doing extensive research, I found it to be the most &quot;set it and forget it&quot; of the incubators that I could find. Many people opt to get a second temperature/humidity reader for their incubator, but I have been completely fine relying on the Genesis' readings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;I also like to use the Hatchabatch app to track the hatch.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/raisingquailsincubator.jpg&quot;&gt;If you are incubating your eggs, it is important to decide if you want to hand-turn or auto-turn your eggs. The Hovabator Genesis will turn the eggs for you, so the only thing you will need to monitor is humidity. Unless you have a power outage or something drastic happens, the temperature will remain quite constant at the level you set it at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coturnix quail eggs take less time to incubate than chicken eggs, at only 17 days. Mine hatched on day 18, and people have reported hatching anywhere within 17-19 days. If hatching happens too much earlier or later than this general window, it can indicate an issue with the incubator environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;You want to be sure that your incubator is 99.5 degrees for the first 14 days, with 40-50% humidity.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/raisingquails2.jpg&quot;&gt;Some people will do a &quot;dry incubation&quot; with quail eggs, but I personally found success with higher humidity. After 14 days, for the final 3 days, you will need to raise the humidity to 65% and remove the egg turning mechanism, if you are auto-turning. This makes it so that the difference in moisture between the inside of the egg and the outside of the egg are relatively similar. If the inside of the egg is wetter than the air in the incubator, you risk &quot;shrink wrapping&quot; your chicks. Shrink wrapping happens when the inner membrane contracts over the chick, which can suffocate it and/or make it much more difficult for it to hatch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once your chicks hatch, they will take a day or so to dry off and absorb the rest of the egg yolk. On a baby chick, you can see a little bulge on their belly when they first hatch. Don't worry, they aren't sick. This is their little starter pack for life. Because they are still absorbing these nutrients, they can be without food for a day or two in the incubator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;It is best to leave the chicks in the incubator after hatching for a minimum of 24 hours, so they can dry off completely. Otherwise, you risk chilling them if you remove them while they are still wet.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/quailhand.jpg&quot;&gt;Even if it is tempting to remove them, this gives them the best start on life. However, I would not recommend leaving chicks in for longer than 48 hours. You risk the chicks getting hungry and pecking at each other. If some chicks hatched earlier and are fully dry, you can remove them first, but be mindful of any pips happening in the incubator because opening it for too long to remove hatched chicks could shrink-wrap some of your late bloomers.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Once everyone is hatched, dry, and running around, it is time to move them to the brooder.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Brooding:&lt;/b&gt; Before you move your chicks from the incubator to the brooder, you need to be sure that the brooder is the correct temperature. Quail chicks are teeny tiny, and are more sensitive to cold than chickens. They require a brooder that starts at 95-100 degrees, right out of the incubator. It takes a little time for the brooder to heat up, so I recommend setting up and plugging in during your hatch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set up your brooder inside, sheltered or even covered, with a heat source that gets hot enough to allow for one corner to be very warm. As with other kinds of chicks, quails like having areas in the brooder that are less hot than others, but try not to make it so that one corner is warm but the food and water are placed in a cooler zone. If the food and water are too far from the heat, the chicks can get chilled just by seeking their needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Quails need a hotter brooder than chickens! They need to start out at 95-100 degrees F for the first week, then down 5 degrees each week from there.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/raisingquailsbrooder.jpg&quot;&gt;I like to use heat plates, because they are more fire-safe and are a more natural method of chick-raising (it simulates a mother bird more realistically). I added a link to a heat plate above. They come in many sizes, so depending on how many birds you are raising, you may need a different size. They are adjustable, so as the chicks grow you can raise the height. Since the heat plate radiates heat mostly downwards, I like to start my quails in an enclosed box before moving them to the open-sided brooder (pictured) once they are a little older.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A storage bin with a lid slightly askew will do just fine. Once they are about 3 weeks old, you can move them to the open-sided brooder. Quails grow really fast, so they will be feathered and practicing flying before you realize it. They are fully mature by about 5-6 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;To set up the brooder for the new chicks, you will need food, water, a heat source, and bedding.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/quailinhand.jpg&quot;&gt;I use pine shavings on the bottom of the brooder. They absorb moisture, keep down the smell (baby quails poop a LOT), and are easy to switch out. Note that cedar is toxic to quails and chickens, so avoid any bedding that is made with cedar. You will need to set up a waterer with fresh water. I add chick boost probiotics/electrolytes to the water for the first week or two to give them a nutrient boost. Be sure to change the water at least once daily; the chick boost is best when fresh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the chicks will need to eat a high protein gamebird feed. I use the 30% gamebird starter and throw it into my blender to grind it up into a powder. They have such teeny beaks when they are little that they can choke on (or sometimes not even attempt to eat) the crumbles in their normal state. After about week 2 or 3, I stop grinding up the crumbles for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Note that the feeder I am recommending does not have a jar attachment, and the waterer is specifically quail-sized.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/quailsbath.jpg&quot;&gt;This is because quail chicks are more likely to drown than chickens, and they can also get stuck inside of their feeders because they are so small. They will climb in and get trapped. If you are using a regular chick waterer, be sure to put rocks or marbles in the bottom so that the water level is lower. This will prevent drowning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Moving Out:&lt;/b&gt; Make sure your quails are fully feathered (around 4-5 weeks old) before moving them outside. If you have pharaoh coturnix quails, you can tell the gender of the quail by looking at the feathers on their chest. A plain orange chest is a male, and a speckled chest is a female, easy as that! Other colors of coturnix require vent sexing, which is a separate process. Sometimes, a male will start making trilling noises, and that is another easy way to tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Be sure that you have a ratio of at least 5 females per one male. If you have extra males, plan to set up a separate &quot;bachelor pad&quot; for them to live in together. Don't worry! Males can live together without females just fine.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/raisingquailsaviary.jpg&quot;&gt;We keep our quails in an aviary. My husband built this, it is large enough to house 30 quails, but I keep only 12 in here. Set up your outside quail area with food, water and shelter. You can put bowls or even tupperware containers full of sand outside in their enclosure. Quails will spend hours dust bathing in sand! I use horticulture or construction sand. Sandbox or play sand is not recommended, since it is very fine and can lead to respiratory issues for birds. If the quails were raised together, they should have no problem moving outside!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have more quails to introduce, stay tuned for future blog posts about introducing quails or chickens to preexisting flocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you plan to raise quails? Feel free to reach out to me on email, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/poppysseedsfarm/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/poppys.seeds&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and let me know your quail plans for this year! Happy farming!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;</content><author><name>Sarah</name></author><category term="quails" /><category term="critters" /><category term="quails" /><summary type="html">Raising quails from chicks can be very rewarding. My quails are very friendly and comfortable around me, and I attribute that to the fact that I hatched and raised them myself. If you are able to hatch your own chicks, or are fortunate to purchase some day old chicks, here is a quick and easy guide for hatching, brooding, and caring for...</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/raisingquails_email.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/raisingquails_email.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Woodburning Hives</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/diy%20and%20building/2021/01/31/woodburnhives.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Woodburning Hives" /><published>2021-01-31T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-01-31T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/diy%20and%20building/2021/01/31/woodburnhives</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/diy%20and%20building/2021/01/31/woodburnhives.html">&lt;p&gt;This is my fifth year as a beekeeper and my third year keeping my own hives. I usually paint the outside of my hives and that's good enough for me. This year I got the bug to try out pyrography. I've always loved the natural look of the plain hive body, and I wanted to see if I could get a finish that both keeps the hive weather-protected and more natural-looking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in trying this project at home? Here's how I did it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What You'll Need:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sarah0a4-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;placement=B01945KAOC&amp;asins=B01945KAOC&amp;linkId=b61fa37d891d93d71bef0e72b25f2a63&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=2d2d2d&amp;title_color=ffc7c7&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sarah0a4-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;placement=B07SKK4GLJ&amp;asins=B07SKK4GLJ&amp;linkId=12a4b27c8b3da39d43c70060865dba75&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=2d2d2d&amp;title_color=ffc7c7&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sarah0a4-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;placement=B07PNHV6F5&amp;asins=B07PNHV6F5&amp;linkId=d414426f763be30c8e0866a2cb13df7a&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=2d2d2d&amp;title_color=ffc7c7&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=sarah0a4-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;placement=B001CEMZYW&amp;asins=B001CEMZYW&amp;linkId=c4f3f467975febeaad1abbbbacaeac28&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&amp;price_color=2d2d2d&amp;title_color=ffc7c7&amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Boxes:&lt;/b&gt; First thing's first, you need hive bodies with an unfinished surface to start this project. I order my unbuilt, unfinished hives from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mannlakeltd.com/&quot;&gt;Mann Lake&lt;/a&gt;. If you do not want to order unbuilt boxes, I have included a link above to an unfinished hive set from Amazon that you can purchase. The boxes themselves will need to be finished, but the hive stand and entrance can stay unfinished; the bees prefer it that way!&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Once you have your hive bodies built, it helps to give them a quick sanding with sandpaper. This will keep the surface smooth so that your pyrography pen doesn't get stuck on the wood.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Woodburning Kit:&lt;/b&gt; I had never used a pyrography pen before. The link above is the kit that I used, and I found that it worked pretty well. Be advised that pyrography pens get hot. Like, HOT hot. You may be tempted to switch out the tip of your pen and cut corners but make sure you wait until it has cooled down (or use pliers, gently) to change it out. These things can get to 1000° F, so... be careful out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Process:&lt;/b&gt; Once your hive bodies are prepped and you have your pyrography pen set, it's time to pick a design that you want to burn into your hives. I wanted to start with my logo. I printed out an image of it and cut it down to the size I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/logoprint.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used a pencil to firmly trace the design onto the wood. This leaves behind an indented outline. Then, I traced this indent with pencil, so I would know which lines to follow with my pyrography pen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Now you're ready to start burning some stuff!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/poppysseedsfilled.jpg&quot;&gt;Pick the tip you want to use. I like the small, rounded tip the best for tracing outlines, and the medium-sized, double tapered tip for shading. To trace lettering or outlines, I would choose the rounded tip. Screw the tip in to the top of our pen BEFORE you turn it on! The tip heats up almost immediately if the pen is already hot. I like to set the pen to the highest setting so it heats up quickly, but there is also a medium setting that works well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trace your outline. If you need to change out your tip to do shading, unplug the pen, give it about 5-10 minutes to cool slightly, and change out the tip using pliers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Make sure you move the pen smoothly, but not too quickly. It can catch on the wood and burn in an inconsistent way. The smoother and steadier you are, the better the burn will be.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you are done burning your design, go over it one more time with sandpaper. Now you're ready for the finish!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Finishing the wood:&lt;/b&gt; I advise wearing gloves. The finish won't hurt you, but it is sticky, annoying, and smelly if you get it on yourself. Pour the Miniwax urethane into a tray. Using a natural bristle brush (links to both of these items are above), paint a thin coat on to your hive body. Let it dry for 4 hours. After 4 hours, you can add a second coat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;And that's it! Let your project dry for 24 hours outside, and give at least 48 hours before you introduce any bees in order to air out any chemicals.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/woodburnfinal.jpg&quot;&gt;This process is more time-consuming and labor-intensive than painting, but I think it is worth it! If you end up trying this project please feel free to send me any pictures of your final product through the email, facebook, or instagram links at the top bar. I would love to see your finished hives!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;</content><author><name>Sarah</name></author><category term="diy and building" /><category term="crafts" /><category term="diy" /><category term="building" /><category term="bees" /><summary type="html">This is my fifth year as a beekeeper and my third year keeping my own hives. I usually paint the outside of my hives and that's good enough for me. This year I got the bug to try out pyrography. I've always loved the natural look of the plain hive body, and I wanted to see if I could get a finish that both keeps the hive weather-protected...</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/poppysseedsstack_email.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/poppysseedsstack_email.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Chickens and Quails: How Different Are They?</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/quails/2021/01/28/quailsorchickens.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chickens and Quails: How Different Are They?" /><published>2021-01-28T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-01-28T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/quails/2021/01/28/quailsorchickens</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/quails/2021/01/28/quailsorchickens.html">&lt;p&gt;Chickens, quails. They're both birds. How different are they from each other, really? If you are just getting started with both or either, you may be wondering how to pick between the two or what you need to get set up. There are a few major differences between these two types of birds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Quails:&lt;/b&gt; Quails are ground-dwellers by nature. They love to spread out in the underbrush, quietly napping on their sides with one leg out or sitting quietly, observing the world around them. They are pretty much silent throughout the day. Male quails will sometimes trill, but it is usually in response to high ratios of males to females, overcrowding, or dominance issues within the covey. They may also trill more often in the early spring, because mating is ramping up and egg-laying starts again. The trill is not loud, and many actually enjoy the sound. In an urban setting, the neighbors won't be able to separate the sound from a neighborhood bird, so it is easier to start a backyard breeding program with quails than with chickens.&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;For the most part, quails don't make any sound at all. A little quail trill is much easier to explain to neighbors than a crowing rooster at 3:00 am!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of their ground-dwelling nature, quails lay their eggs wherever they are sitting. Quail-keepers commit to an Easter-egg hunt when raising quails in a ground-dwelling environment. When raising quails in raised cages, many quail-keepers will set up a system to roll eggs into a catch tray for easier collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prefer keeping my quails in an aviary, so I opt for the egg hunt. Spending time in the aviary with my quails is one of the highlights of my day, so I am happy enough to poke around and find the eggs while I am out with them.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;I personally have found success with an aviary setting, and would recommend a ground cage for anyone getting started with quails.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the day, quails will jump and run around with little bursts of energy. They flap and flush upwards when surprised--a trait that has been historically exploited by hunters, who would send their dogs to flush the quail from the bushes in the wild. The quail would fly straight upwards and the hunter would take aim. This behavior is exhibited in domestic quail-keeping environments, too. When quails are surprised, scared, or in conflict with each other, they will flush straight upwards (a behavior sometimes referred to as &quot;bonking&quot; since they will usually jump, full speed, right into the roof of whatever enclosure they are living in and bonk their heads).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our aviary is 8 ft tall to allow for several feet of bonking space. When keeping quails in shorter cages, it is important to keep the roof at a distance lower than 18&quot; or risk the quails hurting themselves by bonking upwards. If you are keeping quail in short cages, it will restrict their urge to bonk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;My personal philosophy, both as a teacher and as an animal keeper, is to create an environment wherein the natural behavior is allowed to occur in a safe and healthy way, rather than to restrict an environment in order to prevent a natural behavior.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why I prefer not to use short cages and opt for an aviary instead. It is always easier to train a behavior in the direction you want than to try to eliminate it altogether!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it's time for quails to sleep, they do not roost. This is useful (and money saving!), since you do not need to build them a coop. They will sleep huddled together or separate from each other, under plants or in a small structure. Within our covey, some quails prefer sleeping inside the small house we built for them (my husband calls it the quail chalet because it looks like a little ski lodge), and others like to sleep out &quot;under the stars&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;They are very easy to keep, as long as you set up their environment for their natural needs and behaviors.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quails, however, are not all sunshine and rainbows. If they are overcrowded, or you have some quails with aggressive personalities, or you have too many males, they will attack each other. It is important to maintain a ratio of 1 male to every 5 females, and sort out any oppositional personalities. When I first started keeping quails, I vowed that I would never keep them again. After two rough months of quails attacking and scalping each other, I thought that the problem was with the quails&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;However, after doing some research and observation, I noted that the problem was not with the quail themselves. It was with how I was approaching keeping them.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My husband got to work building an aviary, and I got to work breeding a new generation of quails from my one calm male. If you are having issues with your quails and aggression--don't give up! Try out some more natural quail-keeping strategies. Give them a ground dwelling and check your ratios of males to females.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;With quails, and really all creatures, I believe that success comes from fully understanding the natural behavior of the animal and setting up an environment that reflects the way that creature wants to live.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Chickens:&lt;/b&gt; Now, chickens are the classic homestead bird. Often called the gateway animal to homesteading, they really are like potato chips. You set out to have only two or three chips and, before you know it, you've consumed an entire, family-sized bag. Am I right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Quails are cute. They're sweet. They're quiet. But when it comes to personality, this is where chickens shine.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don't get me wrong, quails can have lovely, dynamic personalities. But, when I think of the difference between heading out to the aviary and going out to check in with the chickens, the thing that stands out to me the most is how the birds react to my presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My chickens yell a specific call out to me, either my &quot;name&quot; or the combination of bawks that means &quot;I want mealworms, now!&quot;. When I walk in to the run, my Barred Plymouth Rock and top-of-the-pecking-order hen, Pepper, follows me happily around while I clean their coop or refill their feeder and waterer. They enjoy my presence and I enjoy theirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Many people keep chickens because of their distinct personalities, the ease of finding and collecting eggs, and the beautiful simplicity of the tried and true system within which chickens live.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a large, clean run (with a roof and predator-proof hardware cloth), a coop that can house everyone comfortably (that is draft-free with good ventilation), enough roosting space, and accessible food and water, you can easily create a self-sustaining system with about the same maintenance as owning a cat. Plus, they pay their rent in eggs. How cool is that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chickens are noisier by far than quails. They love to talk, both to you and about you. When I'm inside, I can hear them out there having conversations. When I walk outside, the tone shifts to include me in the discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;If noise is a concern for you or your neighbors, and you have a small space or do not have the resources to build a chicken coop, quails may be a better option.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
&lt;p&gt;Chickens can be hard to keep if you do not have enough space for them, and with the tendency to want to grow the flock every year (chicken math is real!), square footage is a real consideration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'll do some more in-depth posts in the future about the process of building the aviary, the ultimate guide to quail setup, and more information about how to raise quails naturally in the future. Which do you prefer? Chickens, quails, or are you like me and you have to have both?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;</content><author><name>Sarah</name></author><category term="quails" /><category term="quails" /><category term="critters" /><category term="chickens" /><summary type="html">Chickens, quails. They're both birds. How different are they from each other, really? If you are just getting started with both or either, you may be wondering how to pick between the two or what you need to get set up. There are a few major differences between these two types...</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/quailtest_email.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/quailtest_email.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>